PARTH PATEL, M.Eng. Computer Engineering (Junior Developer)

<u>patelparth2018@gmail.com</u> <u>www.linkedin.com/in/patelparth23</u> ⊘+1 6478708358

SUMMARY:

It's been almost decade learning and applying knowledge to bring every pixel to life. My Expertise is to provide efficient code, document management, handling clients, troubleshooting technical issues, and providing excellent customer service. Eager to contribute programming skills and IT expertise to support internal departments, enhance software applications, and ensure smooth operations within CareKW.

Skills: Excellent Communication Skill, Teamwork, Flexible, Multitasking, Self-management, Punctual, Willingness to learn. Tools: Java, Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React, nodejs, MongoDB, Mysql, Git, Azure, Docker, Office 365 suite.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Administrative Assistant – Walmart, Guelph

10/2021 - present

My primary responsibility is to deliver efficient and organized support, contributing to the seamless operation of the organization and designated department.

- Diligently managing and organizing documents independently, ensuring accuracy, and maintaining confidentiality.
- Contributed to the planning, design, and deployment of enhancements to existing applications which eventually improved UI interface and increased in usage of new application by 5%.
- Completing paperwork, packing, and shipping the merchandise properly makes 99% score in processing returns.
- Debugged and troubleshooted software issues, identifying and resolving defects or errors to enhance system performance.
- Coordinated with other team members and departments to ensure timely completion of tasks maintaing score above 90%.
- Assisting in the onboarding and training of new team members, contributing to a smooth integration into the organization.
- Communicate with customers, suppliers, and organization employees to exchange information that results in building long lasting professional relations.

WhiteLion Infosystem - Surat, India

07/2020 - 08/2021

Responsible for developing and maintaining client-based web projects mainly focused on backend side using the MVC framework.

- Design and implemented a complete web application in Node.JS as a backend tool, react as a frontend tool and mongoDB as a database to store our data in unstructured formed that streamlined choice of choosing educational institute of abroad.
- Worked directly with a client on freelance to Integrate him the Web Admin Panel with interactive website.
- Developed and structure the backend web services using Node.Js framework of an android application that was based on mathematical tool (Abacus).
- Developed a backend code and a webpage for a mobile application based on farm dairy products. Basically, I was assigned to develop a code that helped the user to order its dairy products directly from the farms and provide some advanced features like day-to-day subscription order, variety of payment options.
- Building this above large-scale project has given me better insight into complicated software systems and helped me build more effective units of code as functions.
- Involved in code reviews using GitHub pull requests, reducing bugs, improving code quality, and increasing knowledge sharing.

EDUCATION:

University of Guelph, Guelph, Canada

09/2021 - 12/2022

Master of Engineering – Computer Engineering

GPA: 8.9/10

Major Course Work: Finance and Account Management, Image Processing, Machine Learning, Optimization Technique (Linear and non-linear Programming), Software Architecture, Cyber Security, Project Management.

Gujarat Technological University, Ahmedabad, India

09/2016 - 07/2020

Bachelor of Engineering – Computer Engineering

- **GPA**: 8.8/10
- Major Course Work: Data Structure and Algorithm, OOP, Database Management System, Software Architecture, Al, Web Technology, Information Security, Communication skills.

CERTIFICATION:

- Certified First Aid Trainer (2023)
- Certified Project Management Professional (2022)